{"tossups": [{"question": "With businessman William Steinway, this non-American composer created a namesake prize for the best symphonic and chamber music meant to encourage turn-of-the-century American composition. This man returned from retirement to lead the Sejm [[\"SAME\"]] parliament while in exile in London. Edward Elgar was inspired by this composer's piece <em>Fantasie Polonaise</em> for his own <em>Polonia</em>, written by Elgar to assist relief efforts in this man's home nation. For the point, name this Prime Minister of Poland in 1919, the composer of <em>Minuet in G</em>.", "answer": "Ignacy Jan <b><u>Paderewski</u></b> [[pah-deh-REF-skee]] (accept pronunciation with a \"W\" sound rather than an \"F\" sound)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man was ostracized from court and imprisoned after defending the defeated general Li Ling, whose campaign against the Xiongnu [[ZHONG-NOO]] went disastrously. This court official orchestrated the adoption of the <em>Taichu</em> calendar system, used up until the 17th century by the Ming Dynasty. This court eunuch wrote a biography of emperors starting with Huangdi, also known as the Yellow Emperor, to his contemporary Emperor Wu of Han. For the point, name this \"Father of Chinese Historiography,\" the writer of <em>Records of the Grand Historian</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Sima</u></b> Qian [[CHEE-AHN]] (prompt on \"Qian\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In the mid-fifteenth century, this city\u2019s Ducal Palace became the seat of the Malaspina family. Forming a Duchy with Massa, this city had a motto translating to \"My strength is in the wheel.\" While ruling this non-French city, Elisa Bonaparte attempted to bolster its reputation by establishing the Acad\u00e9mie des Beaux-Arts [[boh-ZAHRT]]. An export from this city was used to construct the Column of Marcus Aurelius and Trajan's Column. Quarries were often found around, for the point, what Tuscan city from which Michelangelo imported marble?", "answer": "<b><u>Carrara</u></b> (accept <b><u>Carrara</u></b> marble)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This regime hosted their \"Festival of Military Virtues\" in the ancient Panathenaic Stadium, and a period of political instability called <em>Apostasia</em> occurred shortly before this regime came to power. This regime was overthrown after the government of Makarios III collapsed in Cyprus, prompting a Turkish invasion and establishment of an independent state on the island. Georgios Papadopoulos served as <em>de facto</em> dictator of this regime, which was later replaced with the Third Hellenic Republic. For the point, name this junta in 1960s and 1970s Greece named for a military rank.", "answer": "Regime of the <b><u>Colonels</u></b> (accept <b><u>Greek</u></b> Military <b><u>Junta</u></b> before \"junta\" is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The <em>Sovnarkom</em> standardized what a household of these people looked like, describing them as \"Mills\" or businesses which rent out agricultural tools. Yefim Yevdokimov, a member of the Cheka, facilitated the deportation of these \"Class Enemies\" to regions like Kazakhstan and the Urals. The artificial famine and the subsequent genocide known as the <em>Holodomor</em> was partially motivated to break-up this class of people's power in the Ukraine. For the point, name this Russian term for a wealthy peasant who had their lands collectivized by Stalin's First Five Year Plan.", "answer": "<b><u>Kulak</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Kurkul</u></b>; accept <b><u>Golchomag</u></b>; accept \"<b><u>Rich Peasant</u></b>s\" before mentioned; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This politician, who led the \"Frente para la Victoria\" coalition, faced a scandal after Alberto Nisman was found dead after uncovering her role concealing Iran's involvement in a possible Hezbollah bombing in the capital. This President, whose rise coincided with the leftist \"Pink Tide,\" reasserted her nation's resolve to regain the Falklands Islands in the 21st century. For the point, name this second female President of Argentina, the wife of former President Nestor, who lost the Presidency to Mauricio Macri [[mah-CREE]] in 2015.", "answer": "Cristina Fern\u00e1ndez de <b><u>Kirchner</u></b> (or Cristina Elisabet Fern\u00e1ndez de <b><u>Kirchner</u></b>; accept <b><u>CFK</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This character originated in the pamphlet <em>Law is a Bottomless Pit</em> by the physician John Arbuthnot. In one appearance, this character attempts to bring a suit against Louis Baboon and King Strutt, which are satirical representations of France and Spain. An Irishman\u2019s adoption of English customs is the subject of a George Bernard Shaw play titled for this man\u2019s \u201cOther Island.\u201d This character is often depicted as an overweight man with a top hat and wearing clothes in the colors of the Union Jack. For the point, name this character who is the national personification of Great Britain.", "answer": "<b><u>John Bull</u></b> (prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "This work refers to one comedian as \u201cthe funniest dishwasher on the face of the earth.\u201d The central figure of this work, who was friends with Redd Fox, serves six-and-a-half years in prison after being charged with larceny. This book was published over a decade before its co-author examined Kunta Kinte\u2019s lineage in <em>Roots</em>. After a pilgrimage, the central figure of this book takes the name El-Hajj Malik El-Shabazz. Elijah Muhammad appears in, for the point, what Alex Haley co-authored work about a leader of the Nation of Islam?", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Autobiography of Malcolm X</u></b></em>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "At this battle, Doctor John Riker saved the life of a young James Monroe as he bled out from a severed artery. The pamphlet <em>Common Sense</em> was read to the Continental Army prior to this battle. There is no historical evidence that one side got drunk the night before this battle, although more than one thousand Hessians were surprised and captured by the Revolutionary Army at this battle. Washington's crossing of the Delaware began, for the point, what 1776 American victory in New Jersey?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Trenton</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This culture's namesake style of flint \"Point\" has been used to explain the mass extinction of megafauna during the Pleistocene [[PLY-stoh-seen]] epoch. Dennis Stanford postulated that this culture's technology was given to them by the Solutrean people of Western Europe after they successfully crossed the North Atlantic on small barges. First discovered in the 1920s, this culture was thought to be the earliest established society in the Americas until the discovery of Monte Verde in Chile. For the point, name this Paleoamerican culture named for a New Mexico City.", "answer": "<b><u>Clovis</u></b> Culture", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "An object known as a <em>tila</em> may have been referenced in this phrase, which Charleton Lewis and Charles Short claimed used a different tense that included the word \u201clet.\u201d This phrase may have been borrowed from the play <em>Arrephoros</em> by Menander. Said two years before its speaker stated \u201cVeni, vidi, vici,\" this phrase was considered hostile by the Optimates [[op-teh-MAH-tes]]. This phrase was said after the 13th Legion took a step beyond a shallow river in Northern Italy. For the point, name this statement attributed to Julius Caesar as he crossed the Rubicon.", "answer": "The <b><u>die is cast</u></b> (or The <b><u>die has been cast</u></b>; or <b><u>Let the die be cast</u></b>; accept <b><u>Alea</u></b> <b><u>iacta est</u></b> or <b><u>Iacta alea est</u></b> or <b><u>Alea iacta esto</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "During this period, Emperor Go-Sanjo established the Office of the Cloistered Emperor to curb the power of a dominant clan. That system was weakened after this period's Hogen [[hoh-GEN]] and Heiji [[hay-JEE]] rebellions. The Fujiwara clan held de facto power during this period, which was ended by the Genpei [[gen-PAY]] War and began when Emperor Kanmu moved the capital to Kyoto. For the point, name this last division of classical Japanese history during which <em>The Tale of Genji</em> was written, lasting from 794 to 1185.", "answer": "<b><u>Heian</u></b> period (or <b><u>Heian</u></b> jidai; accept \"era\" in place of \"period\"; prompt on specific date ranges from the late 8th century to the late 12th century; prompt on \"Fujiwara era\" before mentioned; do not accept or prompt on \"Fujiwara Shogunate\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Though not Minister to Mexico, this cabinet position was occupied by Joel Roberts Poinsett in the 1830s. Simon Cameron held this post at the time of a scandal in which he was accused of discriminating against the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad. Cameron was succeeded in this post by a man who led the manhunt for John Wilkes Booth and whose dismissal ultimately led to Andrew Johnson\u2019s impeachment. Edwin Stanton was a holder of, for the point, what now-defunct U.S. cabinet position in charge of military affairs?", "answer": "<b><u>Secretary of War</u></b> (do not accept or prompt on \"Secretary of Defense\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A leader of the Alachua branch of these people named Ahaya was referred to as Cowkeeper for owning many cattle. Neamathla negotiated an agreement on behalf of this people that gave them a four-million-acre reservation. A statue depicting a leader of these people stabbing a treaty with a dagger is found in Silver Springs. The treaties of Moultrie Creek and Payne\u2019s Landing were signed by these people, who were led by Osceola. Andrew Jackson led a campaign against, for the point, what primarily Muscogee Creek-descended Native American tribe from Florida?", "answer": "<b><u>Seminole</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Yat'siminoli</u></b>; prompt on \"Muscogee\" or \"Creek\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Near modern Wadi El Natrun, a subset of these people named the Desert Fathers wove baskets in exchange for bread and other sustenance after being inspired by the acts of Anthony of Thebes. The death of Gerasimus [[gee-RAH-sih-mus]] of Jordan prompted one of these people, Cyriacus [[see-ree-AH-cus]], to undertake a decade long vow of silence. In the prelude to the First Crusade, a man with this epithet named Peter led the faithful in the anti-Jewish Rhineland Massacre while en route to the Holy Land. For the point, name these reclusive holy men of Christianity.", "answer": "<b><u>Hermit</u></b> (accept <b><u>Eremite</u></b>, accept <b><u>Ascetic</u></b>s, accept <b><u>Anchorite</u></b>; accept <b><u>Desert</u></b> <b><u>Father</u></b>s before mentioned; prompt on \"Christians\" or \"Monks\")", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "The first civilian holder of this position was a banker named Charles Herbert Allen. A University of Chicago economist who headed the Resettlement Administration held this position during World War Two. Rexford Tugwell held this position, whose holder could veto legislative acts according to the Jones-Shafroth Act. The Foraker Act outlined the duties of holders of this position. One holder of this position names an airport that was closed during Hurricane Maria. Luis Mu\u00f1oz Mar\u00edn currently holds, for the point, what position, based in San Juan?", "answer": "<b><u>Governor</u></b> of <b><u>Puerto Rico</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Actors in this artform are given stage-names in a collective ceremony called <em>Sh\u016bmei</em> [[shoo-MAY]]. 17th-century edicts banned the female form of this artform, known as <em>onna</em>, in favor of the male version, <em>yaro</em>. It's not <em>Bunraku</em> [[boon-RAH-koo]], but the playwright Chikamatsu [[CHEE-kuh-MAHT-soo]] wrote many plays in this form during the Edo period, including the historical <em>The Battle of Coxinga</em>. For the point, name this form of Japanese dance-drama influenced by <em>Noh</em> theater, known for its complex <em>kumadori</em> make-up.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Kabuki</u></b></em> (accept <b><u>Yaro</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Drama"}, {"question": "Votive axes from this culture depicting a Jaguar-masked deity led to the \"Continuity Hypothesis,\" which claims these people's gods evolved into figures like Tezcatlipoca [tehz-CAHT-leh-POH-cah]]. These people's name is derived from Nahuatl for \"rubber people,\" likely due to their creation of the Mesoamerican Ball Game. The San Lorenzo and La Venta site were inhabited by, for the point, what early people of Mexico who constructed giant stone heads?", "answer": "<b><u>Olmec</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Olmec</u></b>atl)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "This politician, who explored Zoroastrianism, controversially corresponded with the Theosophist Nicholas Roerich [[ROW-rick]], a relationship which sank one of his presidential campaigns. In one speech, this man claimed that the coming century \u201cmust be the century of the common man.\u201d On a tour of Mexico, this man promoted the Good Neighbor Policy after succeeding John Nance Garner, before being forced off the ticket in 1944 by conservative Democrats. For the point, name this Secretary of Commerce and second vice president under FDR.", "answer": "<b><u>H</u></b>enry <b><u>Wallace</u></b> (or <b><u>H</u></b>enry Agard <b><u>Wallace</u></b>; prompt on \"Wallace\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "\u201cIf Day\u201d was a simulated World War Two German invasion of this city. The Citizens\u2019 Committee of One Thousand opposed a strike in this city known as Bloody Sunday. The Mounties were called in to deal with that event in this city which inspired the headline \u201cKaiserism in Canada.\" Over 30,000 workers in this city engaged in a 1919 general strike. Along with the Dakotas further south, this city was extensively damaged during the 1950 Red River Flood. For the point, name this city in Manitoba which shares its name with a lake.", "answer": "<b><u>Winnipeg</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, a Hawaiian minister observed a namesake solar effect where excess dust creates a dark ring around the sun. Art historians have speculated that the orange haze in the artwork of <em>The Scream</em> was caused by the aftermath of this disaster. This 19th century eruption led to a two degree drop in world temperatures, and it was heard from the continent of Australia. For the point, name this 1883 eruption of an Indonesian caldera located between Java and Sumatra.", "answer": "The Eruption of <b><u>Krakatoa</u></b> (or <b><u>Krakatau</u></b>; accept descriptions which include <b><u>Krakatoa</u></b> causing a disaster)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "During an outbreak of this disease, Matthew Carey reported on alleged cases of greed and theft by Black nurses. In 1927, the virus causing this disease became the first to be isolated in a lab. Stubbins Ffirth proved that this disease was not spread directly between people by drinking infected vomit. This disease was shown to be mosquito-borne by Walter Reed during his work on the Panama Canal. Benjamin Rush led a response to an outbreak of this disease in Pennsylvania. For the point, name this tropical disease that caused an epidemic in Philadelphia in 1793.", "answer": "<b><u>Yellow</u></b> Fever (accept <b><u>Yellow</u></b> Plague; accept <b><u>Yellow</u></b> Jack; accept <b><u>Bronze John</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One historical legend about this city may have been inspired by Abimelech's treatment of Shechem. While in the form of Diana, Venus once instructed a hero to travel to this city. According to one source, this city was once ruled by a queen who used an oxhide to surround a hill. After its destruction, this city's land was supposedly sown with salt to make it uninhabitable. In the <em>Aeneid</em>, this city was ruled by Dido. For the point, name this ancient city-state located in modern-day Tunisia, which was destroyed by Rome during the Punic Wars.", "answer": "<b><u>Carthage</u></b> (or <b><u>Carthago</u></b>; accept <b><u>Qartaj</u></b>; accept <b><u>Qrt-hdst</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Helen Plane created a Memorial Association named for this work, whose creation may have been inspired by the physician Francis Ticknor. Sixty-five mounted figures were to be included in this work, which was once managed by the Venable Brothers. Little Sorel and Traveller are among the horses in this work. Jason Kessler organized a \"Unite the Right\" Rally to protest the removal of one component of this work, which was built in Georgia by Gutzon Borglum. For the point, name this monument considered the Confederate equivalent of Mount Rushmore.", "answer": "<b><u>Stone Mountain</u></b> (prompt on \"Confederate Memorial Carving\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A man in this occupation named Carl McCunn became lost in the Alaskan Wilderness and took his own life after accidentally giving the \"All is Well\" sign to a passing plane. George Smith Cook first became famous in this profession in the Confederacy after a visit to Fort Sumter, where he created a popular cartes-de-visite. A man in this occupation gained national prominence in the U.S. after debuting the exhibition \"The Dead at Antietam.\" For the point, name this artistic profession of Mathew Brady and Ansel Adams.", "answer": "<b><u>Photographer</u></b> (accept <b><u>Photography</u></b>; accept descriptive answers such as <b><u>Taking</u></b> <b><u>Photos</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 1917, a 20 meter statue of this man was unveiled adjacent to the Victory Column in K\u00f6nigsplatz [[KUH-nigs-platts]]. This man\u2019s testimony at a parliamentary commission in 1919 fueled the conspiracy theory that Germany had lost World War One due to a \u201cstab in the back\u201d from disloyal elements. This man was reviled by Hitler, who referred to him as \u201cthat old fool\u201d and \u201cthat old reactionary\u201d during his time as president of the Weimar [[VYE-mar]] Republic. For the point, name this general and politician who defeated the Russians at the 1914 Battle of Tannenburg.", "answer": "Paul von <b><u>Hindenburg</u></b> (or Paul Ludwig Hans Anton von Beneckendorff und von <b><u>Hindenburg</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "German adventurer Theodor von Neuhoff [[NOY-hoff]] declared this island a kingdom in 1736. William Bentinck signed the Treaty of Bastia, giving control of this island to Britain. The Duke of Grafton's government collapsed in 1770 after it failed to defend this island from being captured by the Comte de Vaux [[VOH]], who won at Ponte Novu after losing at Borgo. Petru Giovacchini advocated for Italy's annexation of this island, where Pasquale Paoli fought for independence. One native of this French territory went on to become the first Emperor of France. For the point, name this home-island of Napoleon Bonaparte.", "answer": "Territorial Collectivity of <b><u>Corsica</u></b> (or <b><u>Corse</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This Ohio-born president believed in a government that treated people equally based on merit as shown by his appointment of reformer Carl Schurz to Secretary of the Interior. This president advocated for the gold standard and vetoed the Bland-Allison Act. When this man's presidency ended, he decided not to run for re-election and instead became an advocate for social and educational reform from 1881 to his death in 1893. For the point, name this president who won election due to the Compromise of 1877.", "answer": "Rutherford B(irchard) <b><u>Hayes</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A broken tablet shard from Izbet Sartah possibly depicts the earliest writings in this language, and the tongue of Ugaritic [[you-gah-RE-tick]] influenced the development of this language. This tongue, the only example of complete language revitalization in history, initially used the proto-Sinaitic script which resembled pictograms but had corresponding sounds. Primarily a literary language following the 4th century, this language has a \"Mishnah\" branch used to write texts like the <em>Talmud</em>. For the point, name this Semitic tongue, the official language of Israel.", "answer": "<b><u>Hebrew</u></b> (or <b><u>Ivrit</u></b>; accept <b><u>Yehudit</u></b>; accept <b><u>Sepat Kene'an</u></b>; prompt on \"Jewish\")", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "Michael Livingston is among the historians who claim that this battle was fought west of its actual location. Tactics used by the Ottomans at Nicopolis may have inspired the use of stakes by one side at this battle, during which one group was commanded by Thomas Erpingham. This battle\u2019s namesake \u201cCarol\u201d references the earlier siege of Harfleur. The Treaty of Troyes [[TWAH]] was signed five years after this battle, which was fought in what is now Pas-de-Calais. For the point, name this 1415 battle of the Hundred Years\u2019 War fought on St. Crispin's Day.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Agincourt</u></b> (accept Battle of <b><u>Azincourt</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The first ruler of this name, nicknamed \"The Restorer,\" suppressed a revolt by Sufi theologian Sheikh Bedreddin. The third monarch of this name had all nineteen of his brothers murdered and buried alongside their father, Murad III, to remove potential claimants. Another monarch of this name employed the Hungarian engineer Orban to build a siege cannon that inspired the later Dardanelles Gun, toppling the Theodosian Walls. For the point, give this name of several Ottoman monarchs, including one known as \"The Conqueror,\" who captured Constantinople.", "answer": "<b><u>Mehmed</u></b> (accept <b><u>Mehmed</u></b> III; accept <b><u>Mehmed</u></b> II; or <b><u>Mehmed</u></b> the Conqueror; accept <b><u>Mehmet</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The <em>Bano</em> case was brought forth by victims of this event, which may have been caused by faulty VGS systems. The Arthur D. Little report argued against the \u201cnegligence\u201d argument used to explain this event, instead claiming that it resulted from deliberate sabotage by a disgruntled employee. After this event, manslaughter charges were faced by Warren Anderson, who headed the central company. Methyl isocyanate from a plant run by Union Carbide killed over 2,000 people in this event. For the point, name this industrial disaster in a central Indian city.", "answer": "<b><u>Bhopal</u></b> Disaster (accept \"gas tragedy\" as well as words such as \"incident\" in place of \"disaster\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This leader's 1998 seizure of the Drazdy complex, a home of foreign diplomats, led to his temporary ban from both European Union nations and the U.S. In May 2021, this world leader forced a RyanAir flight en route to Lithuania to land in his capital in an attempt to detain opposition blogger Roman Protasevich [[pro-tah-SEH-vitch]]. This man's sixth Presidential term sparked major protests that included participants from the Anti-Cockroach movement led by Sergei Tikhonovsky [[tee-koh-NOHF-skee]]. For the point, name this \"Last Dictator of Europe,\" the president of Belarus.", "answer": "Alexander <b><u>Lukashenko</u></b> (or Alexander Grigoryevich <b><u>Lukashenko</u></b>; or Alyaksandr Ryhoravich <b><u>Lukashenka</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "William Marshall lost to Spencer Gore in the first edition of this tournament. A bomb that hit a corner of this tournament's location in 1940 was not fixed until 1947. As part of renovations to that location of this tournament, Aorangi [[ow-RAHN-gee]]Park had a court built and a roof was added over Centre Court. In 2001, Goran Ivanisevic [[ee-vah-NEE-seh-vitch]] won this tournament as a wildcard, while in 2008, Rafael Nadal won a thriller in five sets. Eight editions of this event have been won by Roger Federer. For the point, name this London grass court Grand Slam tournament in tennis.", "answer": "The Championships, <b><u>Wimbledon</u></b> (prompt on \"All England Club\"; prompt on \"The Championships\")", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Carl Magee [[mah-GEE]], the inventor of the first usable parking meter, helped bring attention to this scandal. After this event, Congress gained the power to subpoena any citizen's tax records. Montana senator Thomas Walsh led an investigation into this event, which resulted in the imprisonment of Secretary of the Interior Albert Fall. Involving improper leasing of Navy Oil fields to Harry Sinclair and Edward Doheny [[doh-HEE-nee]], for the point, what bribery scandal occurred during the presidency of Warren G. Harding?", "answer": "<b><u>Teapot Dome</u></b> scandal", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Fireworks celebrating this event led to 132 deaths in the Place de la Concorde. One participant in this event, which took place in the Royal Chapel, had earlier prepared for it in the Queen\u2019s State Apartments. A banquet in a Gabriel-designed opera house celebrated this 1770 event overseen by the Archbishop of Reims. Rumors circulated that an intervention by Joseph II seven years after this event led to its consummation. For the point, name this 1770 event in which a daughter of Maria Theresa entered into a union with the Dauphin [[doh-FAHN]] of France.", "answer": "<b><u>Marriage</u></b> of <b><u>Marie-Antoinette</u></b> to <b><u>Louis XVI</u></b> of France (accept \u201cDauphin\u201d in place of \u201cLouis XVI\u201d before mentioned; accept \"Louis-Auguste\" in place of \"Louis XVI\"; accept <b><u>Maria Antonia</u></b> Josepha Johanna in place of <b><u>Marie Antoinette</u></b>; accept synonyms for <b><u>marriage</u></b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A group of people with this profession made up the Albion Hall Group, which was led by the leader of a \"Bloody Tuesday\" strike named Harry Bridges. Police clashed with members of this profession along the Embarcadero [[em-bar-kah-DEH-row]] in San Francisco during the 1934 West Coast strike. Members of this profession created unions like the ILA and ILWU. The corruption and union violence among people in this profession in Hoboken, New Jersey was documented in the film <em>On the Waterfront</em>. For the point, name this profession of manual laborers who typically load and unload ships.", "answer": "<b><u>Stevedore</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Longshoremen</u></b>; accept <b><u>Docker</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Dockworker</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Waterfront</u></b> workers; prompt on \"Sailor\" or any profession indicating \"Maritime\" or \"Sea\" work)", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}